A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, Field Offices, New Delhi, India, RG 6, SG 7 FA396
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Indian Agricultural Program - Personnel Files, 1956-1973; I7; 24 __Boxes __9.6 cubic feet
  - Indian Agricultural Program - Personnel Files - Temporary Staff Members, 1957-1972; 7.02
    - Kellogg, C. E., 1957-1959, 1962 (Box 120, Folder 855)
    - Kellogg, C. E., 1957-1959, 1962 (Box 120, Folder 856)
    - Knipling, E. F., 1963-1964 (Box 120, Folder 857)
    - Krantz, B. A., 1957-1967 (Box 120, Folder 858)
    - Krantz, B. A., 1957-1967 (Box 120, Folder 859)
    - McCuistion, Willis L., 1967-1970 (Box 120, Folder 860)
    - Mellor, John W., 1963-1964, 1966-1967 (Box 120, Folder 861)
    - Miner, Gordon S., 1969-1971 (Box 120, Folder 862)
    - Myers, Will M., 1959 (Box 121, Folder 863)
    - Myers, Will M., 1959 (Box 121, Folder 864)
    - Niederhauser, John S., 1964-1967 (Box 121, Folder 865)
    - Niederhauser, John S., 1964-1967 (Box 121, Folder 866)
    - Niederhauser, John S., 1964-1967 (Box 121, Folder 867)
    - Niederhauser, John S., 1964-1967 (Box 121, Folder 868)
    - Palmer, Louis T., 1969-1971 (Box 121, Folder 869)
    - Palmer, Louis T., 1969-1971 (Box 121, Folder 870)
    - Parker, Dorothy, 1956, 1958-1960, 1962-1964 (Box 121, Folder 871)
    - Perry, J. P., 1957-1958 (Box 122, Folder 872)
    - Pickett, Robert C., 1962-1967 (Box 122, Folder 873)
    - Pound, Glen S., 1962-1963, 1965, 1967 (Box 122, Folder 874)
    - Prescott, Jon M., 1969-1971 (Box 122, Folder 875)
    - Raski, Dewey J., 1962-1965 (Box 122, Folder 876)
    - Raski, Dewey J., 1962-1965 (Box 122, Folder 877)
    - Rawlins, W. A., 1965-1968 (Box 122, Folder 878)
    - Ritcher, P. O., 1958-1961 (Box 122, Folder 879)
    - Robinson, H. F., 1960-1961, 1964-1965 (Box 123, Folder 880)
    - Rupert, Joseph A., 1967 (Box 123, Folder 881)
    - Smock, R. M., 1957 (Box 123, Folder 882)
    - Soto, P. E., 1969-1972 (Box 123, Folder 883)
    - Soto, P. E., 1969-1972 (Box 123, Folder 884)
    - Stakman, Elvin C., 1957-1959, 1966-1969 (Box 123, Folder 885)
    - Streeter, C. P., 1968-1971 (Box 123, Folder 886)
    - Swingle, H. S., 1960-1961 (Box 123, Folder 887)
    - Ullstrup, A. J., 1960-1961, 1966 (Box 123, Folder 888)
    - Webster, Orrin J., 1962-1963 (Box 124, Folder 889)
    - Weisblat, A. M., 1969, 1971 (Box 124, Folder 890)
    - Wilcoxon, R. D., 1968-1969 (Box 124, Folder 891)
    - Young, Hong Yip, 1968-1969 (Box 124, Folder 892)
  - Indian Agricultural Program - Personnel Files - Local Employees (Administrative and Service), ca. 1956-1973; 7.03
    - A, 1956-1973 (Box 124, Folder 893)
    - Bahadur-Bajaj, 1956-1973 (Box 124, Folder 894)
    - Bahadur-Bajaj, 1956-1973 (Box 124, Folder 895)
    - Bakshi-Balasubramaniam, T. S., 1956-1973 (Box 124, Folder 896)
    - Balasubramanian, V.-Bhatia, K., 1956-1973 (Box 125, Folder 897)
    - Bhatia, R.-Bose, 1956-1973 (Box 125, Folder 898)
    - Chand, 1956-1973 (Box 125, Folder 899)
    - Chandwani-Chowdhuri, 1956-1973 (Box 125, Folder 900)
    - Chari-Chopra, 1956-1973 (Box 125, Folder 901)
    - Datt-Dhingra, 1956-1973 (Box 125, Folder 902)
    - Dias-Dunkley, 1956-1973 (Box 125, Folder 903)
    - Francis-Gill, 1956-1973 (Box 126, Folder 904)
    - Gladwin-Hardwari, 1956-1973 (Box 126, Folder 905)
    - Hiralal-Janardhanan, 1956-1973 (Box 126, Folder 906)
    - John-Kalra, 1956-1973 (Box 126, Folder 907)
    - Khanna-Kiran, 1956-1973 (Box 126, Folder 908)
    - Kishore-Kurian, 1956-1973 (Box 126, Folder 909)
    - Lal, B.-Lal, C., 1956-1973 (Box 126, Folder 910)
    - Lal, S.-Louis, 1956-1973 (Box 126, Folder 911)
    - Madau-Malhotra, B., 1956-1973 (Box 127, Folder 912)
    - Malhotra, O.-Manuel, 1956-1973 (Box 127, Folder 913)
    - Marwah-Mehta, 1956-1973 (Box 127, Folder 914)
    - Mukherjee-Murthy, 1956-1973 (Box 127, Folder 915)
    - Nagarajan-Nair, K., 1956-1973 (Box 127, Folder 916)
    - Nair, N.-Nambiar, 1956-1973 (Box 127, Folder 917)
    - Natarajan-Niwas, 1956-1973 (Box 128, Folder 918)
    - Pal-Pandey, 1956-1973 (Box 128, Folder 919)
    - Paul-Parishith, 1956-1973 (Box 128, Folder 920)
    - Prahlad-Raghavan, 1956-1973 (Box 128, Folder 921)
    - Rai, B.-Rai, G., 1956-1973 (Box 128, Folder 922)
    - Rai, J.-Raj, 1956-1973 (Box 128, Folder 923)
    - Rajamani-Rajan, 1956-1973 (Box 128, Folder 924)
    - Ram-Ramanathan, 1956-1973 (Box 129, Folder 925)
    - Rangaswami-Rao, R., 1956-1973 (Box 129, Folder 926)
    - Rao, V.-Roy, 1956-1973 (Box 129, Folder 927)
    - Sakhota-Sekhon, 1956-1973 (Box 129, Folder 928)
    - Sharma, M.-Sharma, S., 1956-1973 (Box 129, Folder 929)
    - Shmsuddin-Singh, A., 1956-1973 (Box 129, Folder 930)
    - Singh, B.-Sourirajan, 1956-1973 (Box 130, Folder 931)
    - Singh, B.-Sourirajan, 1956-1973 (Box 130, Folder 932)
    - Singh, B.-Sourirajan, 1956-1973 (Box 130, Folder 933)
    - Singh, B.-Sourirajan, 1956-1973 (Box 130, Folder 934)
    - Singh, B.-Sourirajan, 1956-1973 (Box 130, Folder 935)
    - Singh, B.-Sourirajan, 1956-1973 (Box 130, Folder 936)
    - Singh, B.-Sourirajan, 1956-1973 (Box 130, Folder 937)
    - Srinivasan, P.-Srinivasan, T. K., 1956-1973 (Box 131, Folder 938)
    - Sundaresan-Swaminathan, 1956-1973 (Box 131, Folder 939)
    - Swamy-Vaidyanathan, 1956-1973 (Box 131, Folder 940)
    - Viswanathan-Xavier, 1956-1973 (Box 131, Folder 941)
  - Indian Agricultural Program - Personnel Files - Temporary Technical Employees, 1956-1973; 7.04
    - Agarwal-Anand, 1956-1973 (Box 131, Folder 942)
    - Aurora-Ayengar, 1956-1973 (Box 131, Folder 943)
    - Bahadur-Basha, 1956-1973 (Box 131, Folder 944)
    - Bhadula-Bhatnagar, 1956-1973 (Box 132, Folder 945)
    - Bhatt-Chowdhury, 1956-1973 (Box 132, Folder 946)
    - Deo-Deshmukh, 1956-1973 (Box 132, Folder 947)
    - George-Gupta, 1956-1973 (Box 132, Folder 948)
    - Handoo-Iyer, 1956-1973 (Box 132, Folder 949)
    - Jagdish-Kamra, 1956-1973 (Box 132, Folder 950)
    - Kapoor-Kaw, 1956-1973 (Box 132, Folder 951)
    - Khare-Koshy, 1956-1973 (Box 132, Folder 952)
    - Kumari-Manwani, 1956-1973 (Box 132, Folder 953)
    - Matai-Minocha, 1956-1973 (Box 133, Folder 954)
    - Mishra-Mukewar, 1956-1973 (Box 133, Folder 955)
    - Mukhejee-Nagarajan, 1956-1973 (Box 133, Folder 956)
    - Nambiar-Nigam, 1956-1973 (Box 133, Folder 957)
    - Notaney-Pandya, 1956-1973 (Box 133, Folder 958)
    - Parvathy-Puri, 1956-1973 (Box 133, Folder 959)
    - Rahman-Rana, 1956-1973 (Box 133, Folder 960)
    - Rao, D.-Rao, V. R., 1956-1973 (Box 133, Folder 961)
    - Rao, V. S.-Reddy, 1956-1973 (Box 134, Folder 962)
    - Roy-Sajnani, 1956-1973 (Box 134, Folder 963)
    - Samuel-Sardana, 1956-1973 (Box 134, Folder 964)
    - Sawhney-Seth, 1956-1973 (Box 134, Folder 965)
    - Shah-Sharma, 1956-1973 (Box 134, Folder 966)
    - Siddiqi-Sikaud, 1956-1973 (Box 134, Folder 967)
    - Singh, A.-Singh, V. P., 1956-1973 (Box 134, Folder 968)
    - Singh, A.-Singh, V. P., 1956-1973 (Box 134, Folder 969)
    - Singh, A.-Singh, V. P., 1956-1973 (Box 134, Folder 970)
    - Singh, Vijai-Sriharinarayana, 1956-1973 (Box 135, Folder 971)
    - Srivastava-Thakare, 1956-1973 (Box 135, Folder 972)
    - Tiwari-Utkhede, 1956-1973 (Box 135, Folder 973)
    - Venkateswarlu-Yayathi, 1956-1973 (Box 135, Folder 974)
    - Temporary Personnel - Miscellaneous Programs, 1967-1973 (Box 135, Folder 975)
  - Indian Agricultural Program - Personnel Files - Technical Employees, Rice Program, 1966-1976; 7.05
    - Technical Employees - 1966 Hires, 1966-1969 (Box 135, Folder 976)
    - Technical Employees - 1967 Hires, 1967, 1969, 1975-1976 (Box 135, Folder 977)
    - Technical Employees - 1968 Hires, 1968-1969 (Box 135, Folder 978)
    - Technical Employees - 1969 Hires, 1968-1970, 1973 (Box 135, Folder 979)
    - Technical Employees - 1970 Hires, 1970-1971 (Box 136, Folder 980)
    - Technical Employees - 1970 Hires, 1970-1971 (Box 136, Folder 981)
    - Technical Employees - 1971 Hires, 1971-1972 (Box 136, Folder 982)
    - Technical Employees - 1972 Hires, 1972-1973 (Box 136, Folder 983)
    - Technical Employees - 1972 Hires, 1972-1973 (Box 136, Folder 984)
    - Technical Employees - 1973 Hires, 1973-1975 (Box 136, Folder 985)
    - Technical Employees - 1973 Hires, 1973-1975 (Box 136, Folder 986)
    - Technical Employees - 1974 Hires, 1974-1975 (Box 137, Folder 987)
    - Technical Employees - 1975 Hires, 1974-1975 (Box 137, Folder 988)
- Medical and Natural Sciences Program - Administrative Files, 1935-1973; II1; 2 __Boxes __0.4 cubic feet
  Records in Subgroup II, Medical and Natural Sciences Program, offer evidence of the RF's increasing support for medical education and public health, recognized by the creation in 1951 of the Division of Medicine and Public Health (MEPH).
  Series 1, Administrative Files, dates from 1935, the year in which the RF began operations in New Delhi. Annual reports (1935-1973) from the RF's Representative in New Delhi to the Government of India provide valuable summaries of work in progress and identify current office staff. In their correspondence (1957-1958), John C. Bugher, director (1955-1959) of MEPH, and John M. Weir, Associate Director (1955-1959), discuss the desirability of combining the medical and agricultural programs in one New Delhi office. Other correspondents include LeRoy R. Allen, Representative in India and Consultant to the AIIMS (1960-1967), and Lucien A. Gregg, Adviser to the Director of the AIIMS (1958-1962).
  - Annual Reports to Government of India, 1935-1973 (Box 138, Folder 989)
  - Correspondence - Fellowships, 1949-1967 (Box 138, Folder 990)
  - Correspondence - Fellowships, 1949-1967 (Box 138, Folder 991)
  - Correspondence - General Policy, 1950-1966 (Box 138, Folder 992)
  - Correspondence - Grants-in-Aid, 1950, 1953, 1956-1958, 1960-1962, 1964-1966 (Box 138, Folder 993)
  - Correspondence - Health Minister, 1954-1960 (Box 138, Folder 994)
  - Correspondence - Import Regulations, 1961-1962 (Box 138, Folder 995)
  - Correspondence - Office Establishment - Joint Indian Agricultural Program(IAP)/Medical and Natural Sciences (MNS), 1957-1958 (Box 138, Folder 996)
  - Correspondence - Program Development, 1950-1960 (Box 138, Folder 997)
  - Correspondence - Program Development, 1961-1963 (Box 138A, Folder 998)
  - Correspondence - Staff Assignments - Allen, LeRoy R., 1960-1971 (Box 138A, Folder 999)
  - Correspondence - Staff Assignments - Gregg, Lucien A., 1957-1962 (Box 138A, Folder 1000)
- Medical and Natural Sciences Program - All India Institute of Medical Sciences (AIIMS), 1957-1973, n.d.; II2; 4 __Boxes __1.8 cubic feet
  Files in Series 2, All India Institute of Medical Sciences, relate to three cooperative programs of the AIIMS: the Comprehensive Rural Health Services Project at Ballabhgarh (1960-1973), the joint Harvard-AIIMS project to study health and population pressures in rural communities (1966-1967), and a staff exchange program with the Massachusetts General Hospital (1962, 1964-1967), which was never implemented. The Ballabhgarh project is the most fully documented. This was a cooperative program of the AIIMS, the Government of Hariana, and the RF, which sought to build and operate rural health centers and conduct family planning studies. LeRoy R. Allen served as Project Director. Files include data on family planning (1965-1967), site plans for hospital construction (1964-1965), budget summaries (1964-1968), and correspondence with temporary field staff.
  - General Correspondence, 1957-1964 (Box 139, Folder 1001)
  - General Correspondence, 1957-1964 (Box 139, Folder 1002)
  - Ballabhgarh Rural Health Centers - General, 1960-1973 (Box 139, Folder 1003)
  - Ballabhgarh Rural Health Centers - General, 1960-1973 (Box 139, Folder 1004)
  - Ballabhgarh Rural Health Centers - General, 1960-1973 (Box 139, Folder 1005)
  - Ballabhgarh Rural Health Centers - General, 1960-1973 (Box 139, Folder 1006)
  - Ballabhgarh Rural Health Centers - General, 1960-1973 (Box 139, Folder 1007)
  - Ballabhgarh Rural Health Centers - Architectural Services, 1968-1970 (Box 139, Folder 1008)
  - Ballabhgarh Rural Health Centers - Budgets and Budget Summaries, 1964-1968 (Box 140, Folder 1009)
  - Ballabhgarh Rural Health Centers - Budgets and Budget Summaries, 1964-1968 (Box 140, Folder 1010)
  - Ballabhgarh Rural Health Centers - Budgets and Budget Summaries, 1964-1968 (Box 140, Folder 1011)
  - Ballabhgarh Rural Health Centers - Budgets and Budget Summaries, 1964-1968 (Box 140, Folder 1012)
  - Ballabhgarh Rural Health Centers - Family Planning Studies, 1965-1967 (Box 140, Folder 1013)
  - Ballabhgarh Rural Health Centers - Hospital Construction, 1969-1970 (Box 140, Folder 1014)
  - Ballabhgarh Rural Health Centers - Project Staff, 1965-1967 (Box 140, Folder 1015)
  - Ballabhgarh Rural Health Centers - Supplies and Equipment, 1967-1969 (Box 140, Folder 1016)
  - Harvard-AIIMS Population Studies, 1966-1967 (Box 140, Folder 1017)
  - Harvard-AIIMS Population Studies, 1966-1967 (Box 140, Folder 1018)
  - Massachusetts General Hospital-AIIMS Project, 1962, 1964-1967 (Box 140, Folder 1019)
  - Post-Graduate Nursing Course, 1960-1961, 1965-1968 (Box 141, Folder 1020)
  - Post-Graduate Nursing Course, 1960-1961, 1965-1968 (Box 141, Folder 1021)
  - Review Committee, 1964-1965 (Box 141, Folder 1022)
  - Review Committee, 1964-1965 (Box 141, Folder 1023)
  - Ballabhgarh Rural Health Centers - Site Plans - Blue Prints, 1964-1965, n.d. (Box 142, Folder 1024)
  - Ballabhgarh Rural Health Centers - Site Plans - Blue Prints, 1964-1965, n.d. (Box 142, Folder 1025)
  - Ballabhgarh Rural Health Centers - Site Plans - Blue Prints, 1964-1965, n.d. (Box 142, Folder 1026)
  - Ballabhgarh Rural Health Centers - Site Plans - Blue Prints, 1964-1965, n.d. (Box 142, Folder 1027)
- Medical and Natural Sciences Program - Virus Research Center, Poona, 1951-1970; II3; 5 __Boxes __2.0 cubic feet
  Early in 1951, a Virus Research Center was established in Poona in cooperation with the Indian Council of Medical Research. Files retained by the New Delhi office document the center's establishment, administration, and research program. They are located in Series 3.
  In October 1951, Dr. J. Austin Kerr arrived to organize and direct the Virus Research Center. Kerr's correspondence and that of his successor, Telford H. Work, is filed under "Director's office correspondence." This correspondence fills nine folders and is arranged in groupings designated by the field office: New York office, New Delhi office, Indian Council of Medical Research, and colleagues in India. Files include both incoming and outgoing correspondence with these other offices and individuals.
  Research centered on the identification and isolation of Indian viruses transmitted by blood-sucking arthropods. Files relating to individual viruses are arranged by virus name. Interim activity reports (1952-1957) provide information on ongoing virus work. The Calcutta School of Tropical Medicine and the Indian Veterinary Research Institute at Izatnagar participated in the research effort; correspondence between Poona and these institutions is filed at the end of Series 3.
  The files in this series are arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Administrative Correspondence - Establishment and Organization, 1951-1953 (Box 143, Folder 1028)
  - Administrative Correspondence - Establishment and Organization, 1951-1953 (Box 143, Folder 1029)
  - Administrative Correspondence - General, 1952-1957, 1959-1966 (Box 143, Folder 1030)
  - Administrative Correspondence - General, 1952-1957, 1959-1966 (Box 143, Folder 1031)
  - Administrative Correspondence - Arms and Ammunition Imports, 1959-1960 (Box 143, Folder 1032)
  - Administrative Correspondence - Bank Accounts and Expenditures, 1955-1958 (Box 143, Folder 1033)
  - Administrative Correspondence - Budgetary Matters, 1951-1960 (Box 143, Folder 1034)
  - Administrative Correspondence - Budgetary Matters, 1951-1960 (Box 143, Folder 1035)
  - Administrative Correspondence - Buildings and Grounds, 1951-1955 (Box 143, Folder 1036)
  - Administrative Correspondence - Equipment - General, 1951-1955 (Box 143, Folder 1037)
  - Administrative Correspondence - Equipment - General, 1956-1959 (Box 144, Folder 1038)
  - Administrative Correspondence - Equipment - Donations, 1967-1970 (Box 144, Folder 1039)
  - Administrative Correspondence - Equipment - Library, 1959-1960 (Box 144, Folder 1040)
  - Administrative Correspondence - Equipment Inventories, 1952-1957 (Box 144, Folder 1041)
  - Administrative Correspondence - Insurance Coverage, 1951, 1954-1955, 1957 (Box 144, Folder 1042)
  - Administrative Correspondence - Public Law 480 Funds, 1962-1965 (Box 144, Folder 1043)
  - Administrative Correspondence - Staff Recruitment, 1951-1955, 1962-1965 (Box 144, Folder 1044)
  - Administrative Correspondence - Staff Recruitment, 1951-1955, 1962-1965 (Box 144, Folder 1045)
  - Administrative Correspondence - Staff Recruitment, 1951-1955, 1962-1965 (Box 144, Folder 1046)
  - Director's Office Correspondence - New York Office, 1951-1958 (Box 144, Folder 1047)
  - Director's Office Correspondence - New York Office, 1951-1958 (Box 144, Folder 1048)
  - Director's Office Correspondence - New York Office, 1951-1958 (Box 144, Folder 1049)
  - Director's Office Correspondence - New Delhi Office, 1952-1968 (Box 145, Folder 1050)
  - Director's Office Correspondence - New Delhi Office, 1952-1968 (Box 145, Folder 1051)
  - Director's Office Correspondence - New Delhi Office, 1952-1968 (Box 145, Folder 1052)
  - Director's Office Correspondence - Indian Council of Medical Research, 1953-1959 (Box 145, Folder 1053)
  - Director's Office Correspondence - Colleagues in India, 1952-1958 (Box 145, Folder 1054)
  - Director's Office Correspondence - Colleagues in India, 1952-1958 (Box 145, Folder 1055)
  - Interim Activity Reports, 1952-1957 (Box 145, Folder 1056)
  - Interim Activity Reports, 1952-1957 (Box 145, Folder 1057)
  - Property Lists, 1967 (Box 145, Folder 1058)
  - Property Lists, 1967 (Box 145, Folder 1059)
  - Virus Diseases - Draft Reports and Correspondence - Diabetes Insipidus, 1952-1954 (Box 146, Folder 1060)
  - Virus Diseases - Draft Reports and Correspondence - Encephalitis Vellore, 1955-1956 (Box 146, Folder 1061)
  - Virus Diseases - Draft Reports and Correspondence - Encephalitis, Viral, 1952-1953, 1957-1958 (Box 146, Folder 1062)
  - Virus Diseases - Draft Reports and Correspondence - Jamshedpur Fever, 1954-1955 (Box 146, Folder 1063)
  - Virus Diseases - Draft Reports and Correspondence - Jamshedpur Fever, 1954-1955 (Box 146, Folder 1064)
  - Virus Diseases - Draft Reports and Correspondence - Jamshedpur Fever, 1954-1955 (Box 146, Folder 1065)
  - Virus Diseases - Draft Reports and Correspondence - Poliomyelitis, 1952, 1955 (Box 146, Folder 1066)
  - Virus Diseases - Draft Reports and Correspondence - "Q" Fever, 1952-1954 (Box 146, Folder 1067)
  - Virus Diseases - Draft Reports and Correspondence - Taxonomy of Culicifacies, 1952 (Box 146, Folder 1068)
  - Virus Diseases - Draft Reports and Correspondence - Kyasanoor Forest Disease, 1957-1958 (Box 146, Folder 1069)
  - Virus Diseases - Draft Reports and Correspondence - Kyasanoor Forest Disease, 1957-1958 (Box 146, Folder 1070)
  - Virus Diseases - Draft Reports and Correspondence - Kyasanoor Forest Disease, 1957-1958 (Box 146, Folder 1071)
  - Virus Diseases - Draft Reports and Correspondence - Yellow Fever, 1954-1955 (Box 146, Folder 1072)
  - Virus Research - Participating Institutions - Calcutta School of Tropical Medicine, 1951, 1953-1954 (Box 146A, Folder 1073)
  - Virus Research - Participating Institutions - Indian Veterinary Research Institute, Izatnagar, 1952-1955 (Box 146A, Folder 1074)
  - Virus Research - Participating Institutions - Calcutta School of Tropical Medicine, 1951, 1953-1954 (Box 146A, Folder 1073)
  - Virus Research - Participating Institutions - Indian Veterinary Research Institute, Izatnagar, 1952-1955 (Box 146A, Folder 1074)
- Humanities and Social Sciences Program - General Correspondence, 1964-1973; III1; 1 __Box __0.2 cubic feet
  The activities of the Humanities and Social Sciences (HSS) division in India stemmed from the successful work of the Indian Agricultural Program. Chadbourne Gilpatric, RF Representative for HSS, saw the opportunity to strengthen agricultural education by developing a stronger humanities and social sciences curriculum for the agricultural universities. He also sought support for Indian universities generally. Gilpatric's vision of the role of the HSS division in India is documented in his correspondence (1964-1973) with the New York office, contained in Series 1.
  - Correspondence, 1964-1967 (Box 147, Folder 1075)
  - Correspondence, 1968-1971 (Box 147, Folder 1076)
  - Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 147, Folder 1077)
- Humanities and Social Sciences Program - Socio-Economic Study in Uttar Pradesh, 1964-1972, n.d.; III2; 2 __Boxes __0.6 cubic feet
  Series 2 includes the project papers for the Socio-Economic Study in Uttar Pradesh, which ran from 1967 to 1972 under the direction of Chadbourne Gilpatric, RF Representative for Humanities and Social Sciences (HSS). This was a pilot study of the economic behavior of progressive farmers in four blocks of northwestern Uttar Pradesh. Research files contain correspondence (1967-1972) with New York headquarters and members of the research team, field investigation forms, instructions on interviewing, research findings, and reports. A final report, "Problems and Prospects of Small Farmers in Uttar Pradesh in 1969-70," was issued in 1971.
  - Administrative Correspondence - New York Office, 1967-1970 (Box 148, Folder 1078)
  - Administrative Correspondence - Research Team, 1968-1972 (Box 148, Folder 1079)
  - Administrative Correspondence - Preliminary Report, 1970-1972 (Box 148, Folder 1080)
  - Project Correspondence, 1968-1972 (Box 148, Folder 1081)
  - Project Correspondence, 1968-1972 (Box 148, Folder 1082)
  - Project Correspondence, 1968-1972 (Box 148, Folder 1083)
  - Project Correspondence, 1968-1972 (Box 148, Folder 1084)
  - Interim Reports, 1968 (Box 148, Folder 1085)
  - Research Files - Field Investigation Forms, n.d. (Box 149, Folder 1086)
  - Research Files - Instructions for Researchers, 1968-1970 (Box 149, Folder 1087)
  - Research Files - Miscellaneous Findings, 1968, 1971, n.d. (Box 149, Folder 1088)
  - Research Files - Reports (Manuscript), 1964, 1970-1972 (Box 149, Folder 1089)
  - Research Files - Reports (Printed) - Changing Agriculture and Rural Life in a Region of Northern India - Volume 1, [1968] (Box 149, Folder 1090)
  - Research Files - Reports (Printed) - Changing Agriculture and Rural Life in a Region of Northern India - Volume 2, [1968] (Box 149, Folder 1091)
  - Research Files - Reports (Printed) - Changing Agriculture in Two Regions of Uttar Pradesh in1969-1970 (Box 149, Folder 1092)
  - Research Files - Reports (Printed) - Problems and Prospects of Small Farmers in Uttar Pradesh in 1969-1970, 1971 (Box 149, Folder 1093)